[theme music playing]
[tense music playing]
[screaming]
[shattering sound]
[Anna] Do you know how long I've
waited for this opportunity?
[Ivy] We are not murderers!
If you want justice,
then learn to cooperate.
[Ivy] I have information.
And I know that you'll be interested.
[Emilia] I will tear that woman
into pieces.
I'd like you to refrain from
refiling charges against Arnaldo.
[Diego] Arnaldo will pay
for all his crimes,
whether he likes it or not.
[Ivy] If you kill her, I won't
help you clean up her body.
[Emilia] If you sleep
with my husband again,
I will kill you.
Why don't you sponsor my candidacy?
Maybe someday, we could be running mates.
Why should I enter politics?
It has its own perks.
And you can actually steal
billions of money. [laughs]
Oh, shoot.
Billions?
[Camia] You served as Emilia's secretary
when she was still mayor.
-I was hoping you could help me.
-[Cora] I'm sorry.
-[Emilia] Cheater!
-[Raul] Let's talk this through.
-[Emilia] Enough talk, Raul!
-[Raul] Please, stop.
[Emilia] We're over!
You get out of my life!
[Camia] We're victims of
the Ardientes too.
I'm doing this so that one day,
the citizens of this town
can break free
from the Ardientes' tyranny.
-[Arnaldo] Ivy.
-[nurse] Mayor?
[Arnaldo] Stay there! Don't come near me!
[nurse] Mayor, no!
[Arnaldo groaning]
[ominous music]
I used to work as Emilia's secretary
during her term as mayor.
And, yes, she did engage
in corrupt activities.
Miss Cora, thank you for trusting me
with this information.
But I think it's better
if I take you to a safe house.
We can speak more freely there.
Is that okay with you?
[suspenseful music playing]
[nurse] Mayor? Mayor?
Nurse?! Nurse! Nurse!
Help! Help us! Nurse! Help us! Guard!
Guard! Guard!
[ominous music]
-[Diego] Auntie Camia!
-[Camia] Diego.
You and Miss Cora head inside.
I'll follow.
All right.
-[Camia] Please follow them.
-Come in, Miss Cora.
Please, have a seat.
[Cora] Thank you.
[car arriving]
-Mom.
-Lily.
Are you ready to hear
the witness' testimony?
I'm ready, Mom.
This will be a big help
in taking Emilia down.
Come on.
-I'll go on ahead.
-Okay.
-Auntie.
-Thank you.
So, Miss Cora…
Let's start.
[suspenseful music playing]
[confused] Miss Camia, is that a recorder?
Are you recording this conversation?
Uh…
When did you start working
as Emilia Ardiente's secretary?
I started working for her in 2004.
Mrs. Emilia was the mayor at the time.
Even then, the Ardientes
were such extravagant people.
That was the time when they had
Señor Julio's statue erected.
They were able to extort a lot
of money out of that project.
They got almost triple…
…the amount of the
government's original budget.
But then, their worst act of corruption…
was when Mrs. Emilia
founded the Women's Union.
[tense music playing]
The Women's Union?
Are you sure I won't
get in trouble for this?
[Camia] No, Miss Cora.
We promise to protect you
if you testify against the Ardientes.
What? Testify?!
You didn't say anything about that.
[sullen music playing]
[phone vibrating]
Emilia.
Hello, Ivy? Where are you?
Why? What's wrong?
You need to come here
to the hospital. Arnaldo's gone.
[dramatic music]
What?!
Emilia, stay right there.
I'll be on my way. Wait for me.
[phone rings]
Excuse me.
Mom, I have to go.
Something happened to Arnaldo.
What?
He's gone missing.
We can't let this happen.
We still need him for our plans.
-Okay, keep us updated.
-I will, Mom.
[tense music playing]
[Ivy] Come on. Hurry, let's go.
Please don't worry, Miss Cora.
We're here to protect you.
[sullen music playing]
I think it was a mistake coming here.
[Cora] I'm sorry.
-Miss Cora?
-Miss Cora.
[Camia] Miss Cora!
Let's just leave her alone
for now and try again tomorrow.
It'll be harder if we force her.
[dramatic music playing]
-[Ivy] What happened?!
-Ivy.
I was on my way
to visit Arnaldo in his room,
but he was no longer there!
What, how? What do you mean?
The nurses said they found
the room empty. He's missing!
But how could that have happened?!
I don't know!
Does Congressman know?
[panics] I'll call him.
[phone ringing]
Hello.
Papa?
It's Arnaldo. He's gone.
What? What?!
[dramatic music playing]
Arnaldo! Arnaldo, come out!
Where did you go?
-Emilia…
-Arnaldo!
-Emilia!
-Don't just stand there.
Find him! Arnaldo!
Can you calm down?
What if you get hospitalized next?
Don't act like you're
the most miserable person
on the planet. I'm sure we'll find him!
But where?! We can't find him.
-I'm palpitating!
-Just relax!
[Emilia] Arnaldo, come out!
[Arnaldo murmuring]
They thought they could kill me.
But they can't.
[man 1] Here.
-[man 2] It's the mayor!
-[man 3] It's the mayor!
They can't kill me. They thought…
Mayor Arnaldo, is that you?
It really is him!
Let go of me! Let go of me!
Don't come near me! You can't control me!
[man 1] Mayor come with us, please.
Let go of me!
-[man 1] Mayor, please.
-Let go of me.
Didn't I tell you to let go of me?!
-[screaming] Mayor! Stop!
-Mayor!
Mayor!
-[cop 1] Ma'am!
-[Emilia] What?
-[cop 1] It's the mayor!
-[Emilia] What?!
-[cop 2] Come on, let's go!
-Where is he?
-[cop 2] Here.
-[Emilia] Arnaldo!
Mayor! Mayor!
-[Emilia] What's happening?!
-[Arnaldo] You can't kill me!
-[cop 3] Mayor!
-[Emilia] Arnaldo!
-Arnaldo, stop it!
-Hon!
[Emilia] Stop it! [exclaims]
[cop 3] Mayor!
[Emilia gasping]
Arnaldo!
No! No! You can't pin me down!
[cop 1] That's enough!
That's enough. [shushes]
[tense music playing]
[Arnaldo] Wait, where are you taking me?
I'm not crazy!
-Gently, please.
-I'm not crazy! Let me go!
-Mayor! Mayor!
-Let me go! Now!
Okay.
[Arnaldo groaning]
One of our nurses was badly
injured because of his outburst.
The mayor is dangerous,
that's why we moved him
to the psychiatric ward.
This is Dr. Go, our psychiatrist.
She will take over
the case of Mayor Arnaldo.
Congressman?
Doc, before anything else,
I don't need any more negative reports.
All I want you to do
is to treat my grandson well
to the best of your abilities
so that he can be cured right away.
Pa, we have to know everything.
That's the only way we can help him.
Mayor Arnaldo is showing
symptoms of bipolar I disorder.
Every time he goes through
a manic episode,
he experiences paranoia,
wherein he exhibits suicidal
and violent tendencies.
But we're giving him medication, doc.
Why does it seem like his condition
just keeps getting worse?
Well, his condition can
only be managed effectively by,
yes, medication, but he also
needs gradual therapy.
In other words,
he really needs to take a rest.
And I strongly urge members of the family
to take an active role in his therapy
and to keep the mayor in a calm
and stress-free environment
so he can fully recover.
[exhales]
[Jaguar] You can have the rest of it.
And you, Madrigal, this is for you.
That's all yours.
You did an excellent job. I'm impressed.
They should all learn from you.
-Thank you.
-Thank you, boss.
[sighs]
Let's drink.
Cheers.
Jaguar.
What are you doing here, Natalie?
Didn't I tell you never to come here?
Stay there.
Let me go!
Do you know what your wife did to me?
Huh?
This.
So you better tell
that gorgeous wife of yours
to never be in my way ever again.
Hold on, Natalie, who are you
to order me around?
You talk like you're all that.
Who do you think you are?
You're just someone I fool around with.
How dare you?!
Don't think so highly of yourself.
Let me just remind you,
I'm the reason why you were able
to get back up again.
Don't wait for the day that
I'll take back everything…
everything I gave you.
I will take back everything.
And, when I say, "everything,"
Jaguar, I mean everything.
You will have nothing left.
Not even your soul.
-[dramatic music playing]
-[chuckles]
Grandpa…
please take this off me.
I'm all better now. I don't need this.
Just take me home. Come on.
This is a place for low-level nut cases.
Not for someone like Arnaldo Ardiente.
Doctor, I'm very sorry,
but I think I will have to take
my grandson out of this place.
Arnaldo…
you'll get better.
But not here. Not in this hellhole.
You will spend time in our rest house,
where you will get fresh air,
a calm environment,
and I promise you, you will have
nurses at your beck and call
for anything you need.
You will get well,
and you will win the election.
-[Julio sighs]
-[Arnaldo] Thank you. Thank you.
I… I promise I'll get better.
[Julio] Good.
But I have one request.
Anything, anything. What is it?
I want Ivy to come with me.
[dramatic music]
[suspenseful music playing]
I want her there every step of the way.
[tense music playing]
Oh, Aunt Claire, Raul is so stubborn.
He keeps calling.
How many times do I have to tell him…
-[phone ringing]
-Here he goes again.
-That it's over between us?
-[phone ringing]
Well, what about your promise to Julio
and the condition he gave you?
That you have to fix your marriage?
Or maybe you're still so stubborn
because you still have Jaguar
at your disposal.
-[Claire] Well?
-[Julio] Emilia?
Papa.
I want you to visit Arnaldo more.
And, please, talk to his doctor also.
Tell him to increase
his visits to Arnaldo,
so that he may monitor him better.
-Yes, Papa.
-Okay.
But I'm surprised.
I thought you trusted Ivy Aguas.
That was before.
When I thought Arnaldo could come home.
But to send him away, alone,
with Miss Aguas?
That's another story.
Don't you get my drift?
I don't trust anyone.
Especially not when it comes
to my grandson.
Not you…
and most especially, not Miss Aguas.
Now… I'm going to my room.
Mom, Arnaldo asked me to
come with him to his rest house.
Wait, Lily. I don't trust Arnaldo.
After hearing about his diagnosis?
He might go ballistic and hurt you.
I can handle Arnaldo.
Just let him try. He can't do anything.
There are plenty of nurses and
bodyguards around to stop him.
I'm just worried
that I can't come with you
to talk to the witness.
That's what I'm worried about, dear.
Miss Cora backed out.
But I won't give up on her.
Our plans don't have a huge time frame.
[Julio] I hope I'm not interrupting.
No. No, Congressman.
Uh… I just wanted to thank you
for doing this.
No need to thank me.
Because I really do want Arnaldo
to get better.
Likewise.
Just a reminder, Ivy.
Please, please, bring back
my grandson in one piece.
-Or else--
-No worries, Congressman.
I'll bring him back in
one piece, as per your request.
[chuckles]
[tense music playing]
Auntie?
Lily can't come with us
to visit Miss Cora.
Arnaldo has been discharged
from the hospital,
and they brought my daughter
with them to their rest house.
[suspenseful music playing]
[ominous music]
[dramatic music playing]
[tense music playing]
Thank you.
Despite everything that happened…
you're still here.
Thank you.
[tense music playing]
I love you.
[ominous music]
[line ringing]
[phone vibrates]
Diego.
[Diego] Ivy.
Whatever it is you're planning,
keep your guard up.
If you want to be alone,
there's a garden near the main house.
Thank you.
[Diego] That's where I used to go…
when we were young.
When you were still an Ardiente.
Ivy, you shouldn't have
let Arnaldo force you
to go with him.
It's actually for the better.
This way, I can carefully devise
my plan against Emilia.
They won't suspect a thing because…
I'm taking care of Arnaldo.
[Diego] But, remember this.
If you offer your hand to the Ardientes,
they will take your whole arm.
If not, they will take
your body or your soul.
They won't get anything from me.
I have to go. Take care.
-[ominous music]
-[Ivy gasps]
[tense music playing]
[stutters] Arnaldo.
Who were you talking to?
-Who were you talking to?
-[nurse] Excuse me.
[nurse] Mayor?
-Yes?
-[nurse] Please come here.
-I think…
-Time to take your medicine.
…you need to take your medicine.
[Nimfa] You shouldn't trust her.
What did you say?
This way, please.
Time to take your medicine.
-That's not what you said.
-Nothing, sir.
-What did you say?
-Time to take your medicine.
-You said something. What?
-Nothing, sir.
[Nimfa] She's the one feeding
information to Diego's camp.
-Did you hear that?
-There's nothing there.
Did you hear that?
[nurse] Here. Take your medicine.
[Arnaldo] Did you hear that?
[Nimfa] She's Diego's spy
within the Ardiente family!
What?!
[Arnaldo] There you go again!
-[Nimfa] She's just using you!
-What are you saying?!
You didn't hear anything?
Are you saying I'm crazy?
-No, sir.
-Arnaldo!
-[nurse] Nurse! Nurse!
-[Arnaldo] I'm crazy?!
-[Ivy] Arnaldo!
-[Nimfa] You shouldn't trust her.
-[Ivy] Guards!
-[Nimfa] She's just using you.
-[Arnaldo] Who are you?
-[nurse] Take him inside.
-Arnaldo, relax.
-[nurse] Take him inside, now!
No! Ivy! I heard someone's voice!
-Nurse!
-Go and take him to his room.
What's that?
-[Ivy] Arnaldo, relax. I'll--
-Ivy!
[Ivy] Yes?
-I'll be with you soon.
-[Ivy] I'm fine!
-I'm just hearing voices!
-I know, I know. I'm coming soon.
[suspenseful music playing]
-[knocks on door]
-Anyone home?
Miss Cora!
-Hello?
-Miss Cora?
-[Camia] Hello?
-It's locked. Is she in there?
[Camia] Anyone home?
-Looking for Miss Cora?
-[Jepoy] Anybody home?
Oh. Yes, we are. Have you seen her?
Ma'am, she left early this morning,
together with her kid.
What?
-Do you know where they went?
-I don't.
But they brought a lot of stuff with them.
They're probably headed
to her nephew's place in Manila.
Manila? Do you know their address?
I'm sorry, I don't. Excuse me.
Manila?
Oh, god.
How are we ever going
to find Miss Cora there?
[Dr. Go] Hallucinations.
This is a side effect of your condition.
It starts with hearing voices
and continues
until it becomes
a full-blown hallucination.
But if you continue your medication,
the hallucinations will go away.
Where do these hallucinations come from?
[Dr. Go] Sometimes, there are truths
buried in our subconscious.
And when our
"unsettled business" resurfaces,
it manifests in the form
of dreams or hallucinations.
Why, Mayor?
Whose voice do you usually hear?
What are you trying to forget?
Can we talk about it?
[eerie music]
[suspenseful music playing]
Nothing, doc.
[suspenseful music escalates]
By the way, guys.
We are visiting the home
for the aged in a few days.
This will be our first appearance,
following Arnaldo's incident.
That's right. Batch, I'm sure
your campaign will be a success.
We don't really need to do anything
because you've already
clobbered the competition.
[Loring] I hope the mayor's sick leave
lasts until the election ends.
[all laugh]
[Diego] Even so.
We still need to give it our all.
Because that's what
our supporters deserve.
[Marlon] That's right. Miss Camia's here.
[Loring] That's right, dream big.
[Fernan laughing]
Auntie, Anna.
-Diego.
-How did it go?
Miss Cora's not in her house anymore.
But I won't let the investigation
on Emilia end here. I won't give up.
Diego, I'm afraid of what might happen
in our next campaign.
I feel the Ardientes
are watching our every move.
Julio might even make good on his threat.
Don't worry.
Let's just stay vigilant.
We won't postpone the campaign.
Besides, we have nothing to fear.
We're not doing anything wrong.
In fact, they're the ones
who should be afraid.
Because eventually, their victims
will come to get them.
-That's right, Diego.
-That's right.
[Fernan] That's right.
[Marlon] It's what they deserve.
[tense music playing]
[eerie music playing]
Mayor Arnaldo!
I need to tell her something
about Miss Ivy.
You shouldn't trust her.
She's the one feeding
information to Diego's camp!
[Arnaldo] That's not true.
She's Diego's spy
within the Ardiente family!
-She's just using you.
-[Arnaldo] That's not true!
[Nimfa] Mayor, you need to know
that Ivy is?
-That's not true! [screams]
-[gunshots]
[ominous music]
[eerie music]
[eerie music playing]
[ominous music]
[dramatic music playing]
[tense music]
[Arnaldo] You shouldn't trust Ivy Aguas.
She's been lying to you.
You shouldn't trust that woman.
[tense music playing]
[dramatic music playing]
[birds chirping]
Jenny?
[clears throat]
-[Emilia] Jenny!
-Emilia.
Emilia, wait.
-What are you doing here?
-I was waiting for you.
Haven't I made myself clear?
I still remember it.
I said we were over. You should leave.
Emilia, wait. Let's talk about this.
You made your point.
You're right. I shouldn't be lying to you.
But Natalie's the one who went after me.
Want an award?
But I didn't do anything with her.
I rejected her because I love you.
And where did your chase end?
On the bed?
You're my wife.
You're the one I love, Emilia.
I left her. Let's work this out.
Guards? Escort this man outside.
And make sure he never comes back here.
Emilia.
[slow instrumental playing]
[giggles]
[whispers] Payback time.
[suspenseful music playing]
[door opens]
[door closes]
How was your sleep?
Mine was great.
The doctor's medicine is helping my mood.
Somebody went into my room.
Could be the nurses or the maids.
There are too many people in this house.
Do you want me to call them all here?
No.
It's okay.
I'll just make sure whoever
did it can't do it again.
[ominous music]
If I went into your room…
would that be okay?
Arnaldo.
[sighs]
Are you doing anything today?
I'm in the mood for a swim.
I need to go to Manila.
I have to go to my head office.
I have some work to do.
[exhales]
Sure.
But the bodyguards aren't here.
I sent them off.
Nobody will bring you there.
It's okay. I know how to drive.
[tense music playing]
[dramatic music playing]
[Ivy] I know that was you, Arnaldo.
What's going on in your head, you monster?
[ominous music]
[inner voice] No.
Ivy Aguas can't leave
because you can't trust her.
No! There you go again!
There you go again! Stop it!
-Stop it!
-[inner voice] Calm down.
You are sick! No! No!
-[inner voice] She can't leave.
-Don't listen to him!
No! You're taking over.
You're not taking over.
No! No! No! No!
[eerie sound]
[panting]
What do you want? This?
Let's stop this. You're too noisy.
I'm going to end this. Right now!
See?
[tutting]
Don't do it.
You know, sometimes,
I think Grandpa is right.
You're weak.
Now, let me take over.
And I'll take care of business.
I'll take care of her for you.
For us.
Okay?
I'm going to finish this.
[razor clatters on floor]
[dramatic music]
If Arnaldo really is all right,
then why isn't he making an appearance?
Where is he really?
He's okay, okay? What else have you heard?
[woman 2] That he and Ivy Aguas
are getting married again!
Apparently, they eloped.
Someone saw them in Tagaytay.
So, is it true?
Well, that's true.
They're having their alone time now.
Can we not talk about them? What else?
What other rumors have you heard?
[woman 3] How about Raul?
How is your annulment going?
You know, just eat.
You're making me lose my appetite.
[women chuckling]
Oh.
-[Jerry] Wait!
-Oh! Don't touch me!
I don't have
any bad intentions. I'm sorry.
-And who are you?
-I'm Jerry Dimalanta.
I want to talk to the mayor.
Have you scheduled an appointment?
-No.
-Then you can't talk to him.
And do I look like his secretary
who schedules his appointments?
[sighs] Excuse me, mister.
We're not a church
that's open to everyone.
We're busy!
Yes, ma'am.
Close the door! Close the door! Hurry!
Mom, there's a change of plans.
I'm leaving this place.
[Camia] What?
What happened, dear?
What about your agreement…
with the Ardientes?
Arnaldo tried to kill me last night.
What?!
I didn't see him,
but someone entered my room
and tried to choke me.
And I know that it was Arnaldo.
He's the only one who's capable
of doing that to me.
[Camia] That bastard.
You made the right choice.
Get away from him.
Just come back here, Lily.
Yes, Mom. Bye.
[suspenseful music playing]
[ominous music]
[dramatic music]
Are you testing me, Arnaldo?
[ominous music]
[suspenseful music playing]
Hon! You came back! Perfect timing!
I am cooking your favorite.
Steak for two?
I know I'm a little rusty,
but I know how to prepare this.
So, just relax. I know you'll love it.
Let me serve you.
-[sizzles]
-There you go.
All right. Looks good.
What's wrong?
Oh! Wait! [chuckles] I'm really sorry.
Wine!
I almost forgot.
Here you go. This is perfect with steak.
Here you go.
You go.
-Okay.
-My tires are flat.
It's like someone
doesn't want me to leave.
Really?
Well, maybe your tires
are worn out so they gave out.
Don't you think?
[ominous music]
Where are the nurses and maids?
The nurses and maids? I got rid of them.
You got rid of them? When?
A while ago.
All of them?
[chuckles] Yes.
You told me someone entered your room.
So, I thought, it's either the maids
or the nurses who would do that.
So, they're all gone now.
And besides, we don't need
the nurses because I feel good.
I don't know why, but I just
really feel good today.
[stammers] I don't know.
And we don't need the maids
because I can take care of you.
Okay?
Oh, and the bodyguards
won't be back any time soon
to accompany you,
so I think you have
to cancel your meeting.
Okay?
Good.
Okay. Perfect.
Oh.
Everything's set.
Cheers.
[dramatic music playing]
[glasses clink]
[Diego] Just tell me if…
you need me, and I'll be there.
No, Diego. I have to know
what's happening to Arnaldo.
I have to know why he's acting strange.
Ivy, please.
It's too dangerous.
Arnaldo isn't thinking straight.
Get out of there!
Diego, I have to do this.
Let's talk again.
Ivy, please be careful.
Thank you.
[suspenseful music playing]
[ominous music]
[inner voice] That was right.
You only did what's right.
You were right to keep Ivy from leaving
because she has to pay
for everything she did to you.
She can't get away with it that easily.
No, she can't. Never.
I love her.
And, you know what? She loves me too.
Okay? No. [scoffs]
She loves me, and she couldn't
do the things you're accusing her of.
[inner voice laughing] You are nuts!
She doesn't love you! She's lying!
She's only using you
and the rest of the Ardientes.
But, since you're blinded
by your love for her,
you can't see the truth.
You can't see that
she's just putting on a show…
so she can take revenge
on you and your family.
[stammering] What?!
What are you talking about?!
Revenge?!
You don't know a thing!
You don't! You don't!
You don't!
[inner voice] Really now?
But I know the truth.
I've known this for quite some time now.
Ivy Aguas and Lily Cruz
are the same person.
[ominous music playing]
[laughs]
[Arnaldo] No! No, okay?
You… You're not real.
Okay?
None of this is real. You aren't real.
This is all in my head. See?
I'm smart. I'm smarter than you.
Okay? I won't believe you. No!
No!
[inner voice] You know the truth, Arnaldo.
I went to the mansion to see you.
But, you killed me before
I got to tell you everything.
You chose to kill me
instead of accepting the truth.
[Nimfa] Mayor, you need to know
that Ivy is--
-That's not true! [screams]
-[gunshots]
[dramatic music playing]
You have no proof, okay?
You have no proof!
Unless you can prove everything
you're accusing Ivy of…
I won't believe you. No! No!
You're not going to ruin this for me.
No! No!
[inner voice] Quit hiding from
the truth and start facing it
before it knocks you down, Arnaldo.
Open your eyes. Open them, and you'll see
that there's only one way
to end your suffering.
Just one.
Kill Ivy Aguas!
No!
[inner voice] Kill her! Kill her!
You're insane!
That's not going to happen, okay?
That will never happen. Is that clear?!
Never! Do you hear?
Never! Never! Never!
Never! Never! No! No!
[dramatic music playing]
[Julio] He's really getting on my nerves.
I am done trying to be good
and decent about this whole fiasco.
I want you to bring me Diego Torillo.
Dead or alive, it doesn't matter.
[Arnaldo] What am I supposed
to do with this thing?
Smash it on your head?
Mayor, Mayor. I'm sure you'll give me
a lot of money
for what I'm going to give you.
This contains the dark truth
about your beloved Ivy.
-[Ivy] Mom.
-[Camia] Lily, dear.
[theme music playing]